Subtitles by explosiveskull
We keep bringing him
sacred food,
and nothing's happening.
I... The Beast,
he's shown himself twice
to the masses of the broken,
and-and they're not believing.
There's no revolution. I...
Dennis, do not be scared.
You have to trust me,
as you always have.
Look at you all.
My name is Patricia.
Now, who would like
a PB and J sandwich?
You do.
Ooh! Boom!
Ooh!
Ah, look at.
Oh!
I am the master boy.
Superman punch, bitch! Yeah!
Hey!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Get out!
You all right, brother?
Ooh, you see his bag fall?
It's what they call
dramatic effect.
This is gonna get
so many views.
That a raccoon again?
Did you leave the door open, T?
I closed it.
Hello?
Yo, who's there?
We about to Salt Bae your ass.
Superman-punch him, Ronald.
Oh, shit.
It's you.
They bumped into me
at the subway.
Can't just let 'em go, Joseph.
Weren't you on
a specified walk?
You can't run this
like the store.
It's potluck.
All things come second
when we're on a specified walk.
The store works
'cause we have rules.
Hey, it was a good follow,
though.
"We gonna Salt Bae your ass."
What a douche.
It's definitely going
into the book.
"Salt Bae your ass."
What is that, anyway?
It's an Internet guy.
He's a butcher who salts
his meat in an elaborate way.
You got dinged.
Good news:
they're not calling you
the Tiptoe Man
or the Float anymore.
They pretty much settled on
the Overseer.
It's cool.
Do not mention
the Tiptoe Man ever again.
That's all he does?
He seasons meat?
Dad, you look tired.
Why don't we save the next walk
for the day after tomorrow?
When we find this Horde,
I'll take a mental health day.
Okay. Fine.
I have a new tenuous theory.
Let's call it
Tenuous Theory Number Two.
The first set of girls
that were found mutilated
at the zoo three weeks ago
happened here.
The second set, here.
Now, these new girls
that went missing
create kind of
a messy triangle,
and where you were waiting
today at the subway
was in the middle
of this triangle.
In Tenuous Theory Number Two,
he isn't in this triangle.
He's coming from a place
that has easy access
to this triangular
feeding zone.
I think he's
somewhere here, Dad,
- in the factory area.
- Okay.
I'll walk around there
tomorrow.
Hey, Dad?
I'm checking
the police scanners.
They're looking for you
pretty aggressively.
Be real careful.
All right.
Philadelphia
has a new tallest building.
The Osaka Tower is taking over
the city skyline.
The architecture makes it
an amazing sight to see.
And on top of that, it's
the ultimate in sustainability.
It gets its power
from solar panels.
Developers say it will
draw jobs to the city
by the thousands...
Audrey, I have to tell you
something.
Audrey.
Miss Patricia said
that I'm not allowed
to play with you guys,
so don't even ask.
I had a girlfriend once.
You don't know her.
We kissed.
It's no big deal.
Stop messing with us.
What do you want?
Vera, don't get him angry.
- He's sick.
- Don't tell me names.
They said not to ask you
your names,
because I might get sad,
you know, after tonight.
Why did you pick us, Hedwig?
Oh, uh, because you're impure
and you haven't done
any suffering.
You know that boy band stuff?
It's... some of it's okay,
but Drake?
Drake's my new main man.
The Beast is gonna come
for you guys
any minute now, and I...
I get... I get to greet him.
It's my big reward for keeping
the Horde in the light.
I get to take him
to the masses of the broken.
I better go.
He can come at any second
and I don't want him coming
and finding roller skates
on his feet.
Miss Patricia would find out,
and she'd get angry, et cetera.
- Thank you for coming in.
- Yep, thanks.
- This is an outdoor dome infrared.
- Mm-hmm.
We can use as many as you want
in the apartment building.
You use a 16-channel HD DVR
in your security office.
One of the tenants
got murdered off-site,
and people are on edge.
- They just want to feel safe.
- Totally get it.
I'm gonna take a walk.
Yeah, I don't think that you
need to take a walk today, Dad.
Maybe tomorrow or the next day.
No, I think I'm gonna
take a walk now.
Uh, you don't want
to take a lot of walks.
You might get tired.
Let your dad take a walk.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Hey, do I know you?
Did you used to work
at the football stadium?
15 years.
I used to hang out
with some shady types
down at the stadium
in my youth.
Turned it around
with positive thinking.
Should I ring this up?
We're gonna have
to close early.
Yeah.
Peak transit time's over.
I missed him.
I'll come back tomorrow
when the factories are let out.
Can come back to the store
and we could do some inventory.
Okay.
I'll see you back at the store.
You guys like cartoons?
So babyish.
I don't.
I like documentaries.
You watch documentaries?
I watched a documentary
about, um, space.
It's real big.
Sorry, bro.
It's him. I saw a room.
It had red clay, piles of it.
It's some kind of factory.
They're all in there.
All right, stand by.
I'll search the area.
Dad, I found a brick factory.
Uh, it's old, abandoned.
- Which direction?
- To the south.
Dad?
You said I could have some.
I know.
Taking everything for yourself.
Take some.
Hey. I...
Oh, my God.
You said I could have some.
I know.
What?
Huh?
Taking everything for yourself.
I don't... know...
Who are you?
I...
am you.
Come on!
Where did it go?
Leave!
Don't, don't. Don't shoot!
We can work through this.
Just put the guns away. I...
What's happening?
I didn't do anything.
My name is Barry.
All right?
We have to get Kevin
to stay in the light.
Just-just don't shoot us.
Don't shoot.
He won't hurt anyone now.
You may find
your way out of here,
but you will have to hurt
a lot of officers.
A lot of people.
No one needs to get hurt
anymore, David.
It's gonna be okay, Joseph.
Take them straight to
Raven Hill Memorial, the West
Wing of Raven Hill Memorial.
Grab that poncho!
No trouble.
Keep moving.
Please, don't. Don't.
- Don't. No.
- Easy. Easy.
Hey. Hey! Hey!
We're cool, we're cool.
Totally cool.
All right?
He doesn't like to be touched.
I can, I can walk.
I'll just, I'll... walk.
Keep walking.
My name is Dr. Ellie Staple,
and I'm a psychiatrist.
This room must look nefarious.
The walls are equipped with
46 high-pressured nozzles,
all connected
to a 15,000-gallon
water tank outside.
It will only be triggered
if you are threatening
or trying to escape.
This is a hypnosis light...
Dennis.
My pleasure, Dennis.
You are being monitored.
If, for some reason,
there's a threatening identity
in the room, the light
will automatically strobe
and force a different identity
to take over.
Who was the man?
He was as strong as The Beast.
The man people in this city
have been talking about.
The only person
to survive that train wreck
all those years ago.
I saw a video of you fighting
near a fire hydrant
that erupted.
Saw you choke.
I think you believe
water is your weakness.
Where are you keeping him?
Everyone is safe, David.
Maybe this will all make sense
if I explain who I am.
I specialize in a particular
type of delusion of grandeur.
I specialize
in those individuals
who believe
they are superheroes.
I've been given three days
to treat you
by whatever means necessary.
I came here for you both.
Yo, this doctor comes in here,
takes over our wing,
tells us all new rules.
Rules of conduct.
How to treat people
with kindness.
My whole life, all I do
is take care of people.
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on. There you go.
We got along just fine
without her, didn't we?
Me and you?
Anyway...
you won't be lonely anymore.
You have two new friends.
Casey, could I see you
for a second?
I received a call
from your foster family.
Apparently, it's on the news.
They caught the guy
who abducted you
and murdered all those girls.
They caught the bastard.
Your foster family is thrilled.
I can imagine how much relief
this causes you.
I'm sure you've been
thinking about him.
I... have been
They, uh, told me to bring
lots of options.
Hey, cutie.
Think you could help me?
I'm Jade.
They gave me a syringe for
my diabetes, but I dropped it.
My hands get shaky
when I get low blood sugar.
It's a little too close
to the light.
Do you think you could
pick it up for me?
Wow.
Stand up.
Let me get a good look at you.
You are so tall.
Orwell and Barry are so angry
with me that I flipped.
But the truth is
we really can do things
that you can't do.
I don't understand.
Hey. Hey. Hey!
I'm Ian.
- All right?
- I'm Ian.
And I'm Mary Reynolds.
We're twins.
Do you know
what would have happened
if she'd have gotten
to that key, you gobshite?
The Horde would have killed ya.
What've you got?
You get a little,
get a little hard-on? Daryl.
Just calm down, okay?
I'm sorry
for being with the Horde.
It's just, it's just...
Oh, do you know,
I am tired of being sorry.
You can call me Norma.
I am sorry about
the whole lying thing.
- Though I'm not lying.
- Bro, just stop talking!
I was so amped!
We almost got you, bro!
Trying to keep him here
with this light thing?
- That's some buttery shit!
- Stop talking.
I'm not
supposed to be in the light.
Uh, we need more time.
Barry is
speaking to Kevin,
trying to get him
near the light.
Is he close enough yet?
The only one who can defend us is him!
Him!
Where is the man
in the rain poncho?
Who is he?
Is he just a regular man?
I need to know.
All right, step away from
the controls now, little duck.
That's fine.
Now just walk away.
That's it.
Just tiptoe away.
I try to come once every week.
Sometimes, I admit,
I have neglected a week
here and there.
He's changed over the years.
I can tell he's given up.
It's hard to see.
He thinks he was a mistake.
I'm not saying
he did good things.
He didn't.
Those poor people didn't
deserve to die like that.
But he's trying
to make sense of who he is.
Ain't we all doing that?
Yes, ma'am, we are.
They keep him heavily sedated.
This is an enormous amount
of sedation.
He's too smart for 'em.
When they first
brought him here,
he memorized a blueprint
left out from an electrician
and short-circuited the power
to the whole hospital.
He's good
thinking through things.
He has this notion
that superheroes are
based on people like him,
and that other gentleman
I read is here, Mr. Dunn.
Would it surprise you to know
there are more and more people
who have this delusion?
It is actually
the center of my work.
Yes, it would.
You don't let them
get you down, Elijah.
You hear me?
Stay proud.
Step back
against the wall, please.
You're keeping him here
without guards?
I have to get out of here
before he gets out.
The individual
who came with you is contained.
David.
I would like you to agree
to have an MRI.
You were the sole survivor of
a devastating train derailment
19 years ago.
It is possible that there was
damage to the frontal lobe
that you are unaware of.
Look at you, David.
You believe you have barely
enough strength to stand up.
You can't possibly
explain everything away.
Madam, I am Mr. Pritchard.
I'm a professor of cinema.
Specifically, Japanese,
1950s through the 1980s.
And I have absolutely no idea
what I'm doing here.
I am very much in favor
of Kevin's reemergence,
and yet I find myself
in a goddamn prison cell!
And I can assure you
I am not...
Okay.
I'm ready.
Young man, wait!
You will not be able
to get to the light.
It is set off by distance
as well as being monitored
by a camera.
I know this seems
very unfair to you...
...but you are stuck
in this room.
The guy The Beast fought,
he's right there!
He can't beat The Beast.
He doesn't think he can
beat The Beast, does he? Huh?
Beast like...
He doesn't think he can
beat The Beast, does he?
Beast like...
Your name is Hedwig, right?
You're nine, right?
Yeah.
Forever?
No matter how many
experiences you have?
That must be so hard.
You treat people who think
they're comic book characters
or something?
I got to go.
Miss Patricia says
she wants the light.
Hello, Patricia.
- I'm Dr. Staple.
- I've gathered.
As I understand it, you're
kind of the high priestess.
This cause isn't about me.
It's about The Beast, is it?
Where is he?
- Who?
- The man.
He is guarded, isn't he?
He can't get out?
He's well-intentioned
and you would love him.
He's, like, a huge,
he's a big trickster.
He's a, he's a,
he's a great guy.
He's got
a great sense of humor.
- So, let me recap what you've told me.
- Mm-hmm.
Your dad is not the Green Guard
or "whatever his name is."
Your dad is a trickster,
and that I would love him.
He thought it would be fun
to be a do-gooder for a day,
pretend he was this guy.
And with regard
to how he found the girls,
you retold a humorous story
where your dad thought
the killer might be
in the factory area
because his friend Lou...
you referred to him as Louie
at a different point...
got mugged down there once.
Then your father was
walking by a building,
hears girls screaming for help,
at which point you spiritedly
reenacted this moment
in the story.
Thank you for that.
Then your father
called you on the cell.
You told him to call
the police, but he was,
"In it, you know. In it."
Right.
I'll sign that
in front of a judge.
So, you see,
he shouldn't be here.
How long have you believed
your dad was a superhero?
There was a microphone
on his poncho.
I assume he was communicating
with you.
He talks to you
when he's out on searches,
doesn't he, Joseph?
He hasn't hurt anybody.
In the eyes of the authorities,
that is not accurate.
He's injured
countless individuals
who haven't had
their due process in court.
And there was a teenage girl
in this latest incident
- who broke her arm and ribs.
- No.
They would all be
murder victims
if it wasn't for my dad.
It was a vigilante event,
and a victim was injured.
They will claim, in court, that
if they had found the girls,
no one would have been hurt.
Joseph, I only have a few days.
If I don't get him to give up
his delusion, he will remain
in institutions like this
for the rest of his life.
No, he can't stay here.
Can I ask you about
your mother, Joseph?
What does that
have to do with this?
She passed away from
acute lymphoblastic leukemia
five years ago.
That was cataclysmic
for you and your dad.
Yeah.
On the surface, Joseph,
you can see
what I'm going to say, right?
You lost your mother.
You believe your father
is a real-life superhero.
You believe
he is almost immortal.
You can see how some would say
you need this to be true.
You just have to make sure
you are not
more into this than he is.
I'm not scared.
That's great.
You know why?
I know now.
Know what?
Your secret identity.
That man was right.
Joseph.
There are big guys
in almost every gym
that can lift that much.
You could've lifted more.
Don't worry.
I won't tell anyone.
Just because he let you go
doesn't mean he is good.
He's being held here
before his trial.
I'm in charge of him for now,
but everyone in this state
wants him tried and put away.
I'm trying to get the others
to stop thinking of this
as a superhuman being.
If they do,
they will do the right thing
and keep him from the light.
Can I talk with them?
No.
Why?
Because it's not...
You're the victim.
No way!
You tried so hard
to get away from us
and now you come back
and see us?
You are so weird.
I like Drake now.
I liked Nicki for a while, but
then Nicki and Drake broke up,
and you can't like both.
This place is
for people who think
that they're
comic book characters.
And the Horde is kind of like
a comic book character name,
isn't it?
Love comic books.
I'm sorry for trying to feed
you to The Beast, et cetera.
It's okay.
Can I talk to Dennis
or Patricia, please?
She was my girlfriend.
We kissed.
Don't worry.
I haven't cheated on you.
What are you doing here?
Your clothes are not dirty.
Good.
Hello, Dennis.
A lot of people have died.
Well...
You have to give up the light.
They're never gonna
let you out of here.
The Horde has to
give up the light.
Listen to this doctor.
The doc tells lies.
We will reveal that the broken
are the strongest.
The Beast will start
a revolution.
Is that what Patricia
told you to say?
The Beast is the highest form
of human evolution.
Dennis. You guys are gonna die.
Casey.
Ah... oh...
Oh, sh...
Hey.
Kevin?
It's you.
You look different.
I wanted to tell you something.
My uncle's in jail.
I put him there.
What he did to me was... wrong.
Just like what your mom
did to you was wrong.
We're the same?
I'm sorry.
- I can't. I got...
- Kevin, wait.
I've got to go.
The Horde is never
letting go of the light and...
Do you like Kevin now?
Casey. I need you.
The power of true,
loving, physical affection,
it's like something
supernatural.
It's the lack of it
that caused this,
and only the true version of it
can heal it.
Will you help me?
You are the last
person I need to see today.
You see this camera?
There are 100 more of these.
Out of respect for
your cognitive abilities,
I have installed cameras
on every floor, every area,
including every direction
of the exterior building.
We will see everything.
There is nowhere you can go
that won't be documented.
Elijah. I've come
to the conclusion
that we should perform
a procedure on you.
This is a corrective procedure
that rebalances
the part of the frontal lobe
that is overstimulated.
It would be an honor to get to
know your perspicacious mind.
We're going to conduct
the procedure in three days.
12!
Keep going!
Right there, right there!
Hey, my man.
How'd you get out of your room?
You must have
left the door ajar.
He rolled out toward the noise.
Wheel him back in
before the doctor sees.
Oh, you're too nice, Daryl.
You got to be firm.
They'll walk all over you
otherwise.
He didn't touch
any of the medicines, did he?
No.
Right amounts.
This will be
my final evaluation.
You got to be kidding me.
This guy killed everyone
on my train.
He's a mass murderer.
I understand
that the three of you
think you are superhuman.
That you don't think
you are normal.
You've convinced yourselves
you have extraordinary gifts,
like something
out of a comic book.
I am here to discuss
the possibility
that you are mistaken.
Can you tell me about
Kevin's parents?
Kevin's mother...
hurt Kevin.
And Kevin's father
was gonna get a doctor
to try and stop her,
but he left.
I never wanted any of this.
What?
The killings.
Kevin Wendell Crumb.
- Kevin Wendell Crumb.
- Kevin Wendell Crumb!
What did I tell you?!
There is no running
in the house,
Kevin Wendell Crumb!
Kevin?
Kevin.
Why do you all
keep bringing me back?
I-I don't want to be here.
The need for the particular
story we tell ourselves
begins somewhere, Kevin.
From a memory.
What?
I don't...
Hey, where's that girl?
Casey. Sh-She...
Everybody wants the light now.
They're all fighting,
et cetera.
And Miss Patricia's
yelling at me,
saying I got to hold on
to the light.
She said I have one job to do:
keep Kevin out of the light.
So, I'm sorry,
you won't see him anymore.
And you have to listen
to her, right?
Because she's an adult
and you're not.
Duh. Yeah.
Is he crying?
Geez, pussy.
Listen, I don't know about
these other guys,
but we are like a superhero.
No? We're like...
We're not crazy!
David, I don't think
this applies just to Kevin
and his disorder.
Is there a memory?
What you're looking for
is a moment of weakness
that made you
possibly entertain the idea
of being super strong.
There is a reason I ask you.
This is your MRI, David.
This is your frontal lobe.
There is a questionable cloud
right here.
There is the possibility
that that is damage
from that train accident.
I'm supposed to believe
this means something?
It's just this,
plus an anchoring incident,
and you would have the pattern
for this disorder that I treat.
I hate to see you like this.
This is not
how I would've done things.
I don't approve of
how they've handled you.
Elijah, because of
your condition,
I didn't have to do
an MRI on you.
There are a few in your file.
You definitely have
one of the markers
for this disorder, Elijah.
As do you, Kevin.
These are the medical reasons
I'm thinking
you have this disorder.
Now let's deal with
why you think you don't.
How do you know who's good
and who's bad, David?
Convince me.
It's a feeling.
An intuition?
When you see someone?
I have to touch them.
What does the intuition
feel like?
A vision.
A moment.
A sin.
You kind of
have to interpret it.
Have you ever seen
very good magicians, David?
I mean, the very best.
They are trained as mentalists,
and they can do
seemingly extraordinary feats.
They accomplish these feats by
interpreting hundreds of cues
that an individual is
giving off in a split second.
I think you are like these
professional guessers, David.
You are world-class at it,
simply extraordinary at it.
But it is based on real things,
and you are making the picture.
It is not coming to you
through mystical means.
These are the clothes
that the patient next to you
came in with when he arrived.
There's red clay
staining the pants.
It's very visible.
Is it possible that you saw
something on the news...
- Sorry, bro.
- ...then saw an adult acting like a child,
someone who fit the bill
of someone with this disorder,
intuited, "This might be
the person I'm looking for"?
Saw the red clay
and thought he might be hiding
in a place with red clay?
No.
You're certain?
You're... creating a chain of
thoughts that never happened.
You really dissected him,
Doctor.
Good for you.
As I understand it,
there were many videos
of world-class rock climbers
on the computer
in your office at the zoo.
It was kind of an obsession.
Some of those climbers
could actually scale
a literal wall, couldn't they?
What's your point, Doctor?
It was a practical observation
that produced a practical
skill set in an alter.
Mm.
Then how did he bend the bars?
The iron bars at the zoo?
You did see those, didn't you?
That's not in our heads.
The cages beneath the zoo
were made in 1874
when the zoo first opened.
I was able to bend them by
putting a wrench between them
and leaning back.
Difficult, again, but possible.
No.
What about the shotgun?
He was shot.
Not once but twice.
What does your sleeping mind
think of that?
We've analyzed the shotgun
and the cartridges.
They were very old.
There was a lot of moisture
from the boiler room
down in the locker area
where they were kept.
The cartridges were
possibly compromised.
And some of the pellets
hit the inside of the bars.
It is at least possible
that there is a practical
explanation for this.
What if I suggested
something upsetting, Patricia?
Like The Beast isn't
as powerful as you think.
He's not much more powerful
than a strong man.
The facts you are basing
your belief in are wrong.
If superheroes exist, why are
there only three of you?
When was the first
comic book written?
The first reprints of newspaper
strips in tabloid size
happened in 1929.
And then, in 1938,
the apotheosis happened.
Action Comics Number One
launched
with the man in the cape and
the blue tights on the cover.
Boo-yah!
Here we are.
Thank you.
What are you doing back there?
You're not one of those
Hello Kitty pervs?
I'm just looking for something.
Prove to someone I'm not crazy.
I'm leaving.
Oh, my God.
- Catch.
- You're it.
- Let's play hot potato, guys.
- Let's play hot potato!
Hot potato. Hot potato.
Hot potato.
Hot potato! Hot potato! Hot!
- You're out.
Come on, ready?
- No!
Hot potato.
Hot potato. Hot potato.
Hot potato! Hot!
I'm just asking you to bring in
a package if you see one
instead of stepping over it
to come in the house.
Hello?
If, by mistake,
I-I drop this...
heavy flashlight
on your paper legs...
...no one would come
check on you for some time,
not until Daryl gets here
for his shift.
Have you been getting
out of your room, Elijah?
I must be losing my mind.
Night, Joe.
Have a good night.
- Daryl.
- Hey, my man.
You almost made it.
I think your watch is fast.
Joe, my man.
- How's it going?
- What's going on?
- What's happening?
- Looking tired, man.
You still taking
that multivitamin?
Not like I should.
Yeah, but, listen,
you got to take the D.
If you don't take vitamin D,
none of that stuff's gonna
absorb into your body.
Clarence Wendell Crumb.
Take a little bit
of grape seed extract,
and it'll keep it all in there.
You'll absorb it
into your body faster.
Let me ask you,
how much water you drinking?
- Not enough.
- Yeah. I know.
How?
How did you get here
without anyone seeing?
The sound of
a car backfiring occurs
when unburned fuel vapor is
ignited by a very hot muffler
upon the car being turned off.
Daryl, who takes over
at 11:00 p.m.,
suffers from this particular
vehicular malady.
It happened seven minutes ago.
Couple that with the fact
that I've overheard complaints
about how long it takes him
to get to his desk...
he's a bit of a talker,
you see...
I estimate I have
two to three minutes left.
Someone has been pretending.
Pilfered the aspirin bottle.
Replaced the original dose
of medicine
with the same amount
of aspirin.
Did sleight of hand
with the pills
given to me to take daily.
What do you want?
Ma'am.
I'm here to see
if the tales of the
extraordinary being are real,
- the half-man, half-creature.
- Patricia.
But I appreciate your manners.
I don't know anymore.
I'm a comic book expert,
Patricia.
I believe comic books are
a continuation of documentation
that has gone on for centuries
of what humans are capable of.
That they are what someone
somewhere saw or felt.
Are you aware that spandex,
the underwear on the outside,
and boots come from strongmen
in the circus in the 1930s?
- No.
- The freak show men
who could do
incredible feats of strength.
I urge you to look past the
capes and monologuing villains.
Are you with me?
Yes.
I only have a minute left.
I believe The Beast
may be part of this.
There are references
to man/animal characters.
The dual character, the man
who has abilities like animals.
I'd like to meet The Beast,
see if he's real.
If he is,
then I'll get us all
out of here tomorrow night.
What's upsetting you, Patricia?
What if he can't do
these extraordinary things?
What if he is just unwell?
Like you.
Everything extraordinary
can be explained away,
and yet it is true.
I think deep down
you know this.
Everything we will see and do
will have a basis in science.
But it will have limits.
This is the real world,
not a cartoon.
And yet some of us
don't die from bullets.
Some of us
can still bend steel.
That is not a fantasy.
Hmm.
If you really think
you can get us all out,
then you may meet The Beast.
But for your sake,
I hope he likes you.
Tomorrow night.
Call a board meeting
or whatever.
What do we call you, sir?
First name, "Mr."
Last name, "Glass."
- What's going on?
- Be careful.
- What... Oh.
- Not too much pressure when restraining him.
Dr. Staple, what are you doing?
- It's a sedative.
- What?
- I'm sorry to do this, Elijah.
- Ow!
We saw footage of you
leaving your room last night.
- No. No.
- It seems you have been duping us.
I've moved up the procedure
to this morning.
Wait, I...
Thank you
for being careful, everyone.
Good luck, Elijah.
Nothing essential
is going to change
about who you are.
I promise, my friend.
Elijah!
So let's all scream!
Ma'am, get ahold of yourself.
Mama!
Elijah!
Stop the ride!
- Ma'am, step down.
- Stop the ride!
Dinner, Elijah.
How you doing?
You'll feel better tomorrow.
Pictures are crooked.
Hey.
Took a bitch-ass long time
to find the right piece.
First name, "Mr."
Last name, "Glass."
You don't know
what it's like, Daryl.
To be so different,
you don't know where you fit.
It's an awful feeling.
Hey there, buddy. What's up?
Patricia told us
you were coming.
My name is Luke, and I am
Team Horde all the way.
Yeah, I can intro you
to everybody.
I ain't no bad hombre to know.
Everybody's gonna tell you
that I got a big mouth, though,
I spoil
the end of movies. Ain't true.
Everybody knows the priest dies
at the end of The Exorcist.
The American Sublime.
Do you even know
what that means? No.
That is why
this world is a lost cause.
That is why The Beast is
the only thing that is
pure and meaningful...
American Sublime refers to
Western paintings of landscapes
and seascapes depicting
the immensity of nature.
The use of violent storms
in the distance
was a common practice.
Painting's of particular
interest to me.
Hey, Miss Patricia says
that your bones can break
if I, like,
tap them.
Is that true?
Yes.
Uh, so what's your superpower?
Your-your mind?
What's mine?
You're nine forever, right?
Yeah.
That's incredible.
You can see the world
the way it really is.
Always.
Kid who can never grow old.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
Whoa.
This place is so cool,
Mr. Glass.
I feel like dancing.
Then go ahead and dance.
Yeah! Check it!
Yeah.
Oh, man.
They've been lying to us all.
You believe?
Yes, I do.
It's what I've believed
my whole life.
They are losing faith.
My Horde is losing faith!
In comics...
you would go to a public place
where all could see you.
A place celebrating
man's pedestrian achievements.
But you need David
to convince them.
You should fight him
in front of the world.
The tallest building
in this city is opening today.
All the cameras in the world
will record you.
You can convince the Horde
and the world at the same time.
We exist.
Why are you
in this chair, child?
My bones break easily.
I was born this way.
I've had 94 breaks in my life.
I've known only pain.
Rejoice.
You have suffered
and are now pure.
I assume you were sent here
to be an avenging angel.
How much do you want
to avenge us?
Well, that sounds like
the bad guys teaming up.
How you doing, David?
I always thought of us
as friends.
Elijah?
You shouldn't be hiding
in the shadows, David.
You're able to hide
because people who steal cars
and mug people in alleys
don't need your full potential.
You're only using
one percent of your abilities
with these petty criminals.
Maybe there's nothing
to hide, Elijah.
I have found someone
who will require your
full potential to come out.
A superhuman serial killer.
Don't do this.
How can we be the only ones?
Maybe we believed something
that isn't even true.
We are going to the
tallest building in the city.
The Horde is going to be
revealed there.
There are three floors
that house a chemical company
in that building.
I am going to blow up
that building
using their chemicals, David.
You might want
to try and stop us.
Today is your coming-out party.
At least you know what to wear.
I've turned off the water hoses
in your room, David.
- There's only the door left.
- Elijah.
It's metal.
But you can't get through it
because people's bones break
against metal,
and you're nothing special.
A lot of people are
going to die, Overseer,
if you don't get
through that door.
Hi.
I'm here.
Daryl?
This is where
they would paint you
with big eyes and bubbles
of confusion above your head.
You... hurt him?
What are you doing?
You should kneel before him.
He is the broken.
Step away from me.
Get back in your room!
Both of you!
You're fighting for the broken.
You found your purpose.
One of the Horde may need
to walk us out of here,
if that's okay... partner.
Go through the basement.
Listen to me, Joseph.
Your father is making
great progress.
I'm very hopeful for him.
Did you know the first Superman
couldn't even fly?
And Metropolis is actually
New York City.
And what about
all the coincidences
in what I was reading?
Comic books are an obsession.
Have you ever been
to a comic book convention?
They sell teen TV shows there.
They are selling things.
Your friends and family members
have lost their perspective.
Your dad is trying
to fight her abductor.
Your son is trying
to best his dad.
He's the anarchist.
He's the brains.
He's the reluctant hero.
This all sounds very familiar,
doesn't it?
Comic books are not
valid history.
Hey, what wing are you with?
Uh, The Beast
is saying that he'd like you
to roll forward when they come.
I believe.
The new Osaka building
opens today with much fanfare.
Thousands are expected
to come out for the ceremony.
Many just want to see
the spectacular architecture.
Now, this building is expected
to be the hub
of the business community,
creating thousands of jobs...
We have a Code Three.
All patients locked
in their rooms.
Grounds security on alert.
The patients
are planning to go
to the public opening
of the Osaka Tower,
the tallest building.
Elijah may be intending
to compromise
a chemical facility there.
Please alert the
Philadelphia Police Department.
They made a mistake
going through the basement.
It gives us some time.
I remember something
about a classic public forum
where the climax
of limited editions end.
Uh, I think he said it was
referred to as the showdown,
where all the skills
are revealed
and-and pitted
against each other.
And then?
What happens?
Christ, they're out here.
They're out here!
This is Dr. Ellie Staple.
We will need assistance
at Raven Hill Memorial
immediately.
No!
How many people
are gonna die today?
Huh?
I don't want to do this.
I don't care
what Patricia says.
I'm not...
Hedwig's taking the light.
Hey, what's up?
Don't worry.
We don't need him anyway.
There are still ten of us.
It appears The Beast
is not done here yet.
We've got eyes on him.
Please advise.
The collection
of main characters.
Keep patients and staff away
from the south-side windows.
Authorities are on their way.
Okay. I got you.
You will learn to kneel
before the broken.
I need to explain.
He has D.I.D.
- He believes he's an animal.
- Keep moving.
No, you don't understand.
All he knows is pain.
You're going to get hurt.
Somebody, please...
He has D.I.D.
We can get the compassionate
people inside him
- to help you.
- Stay here.
You're the girl
The Beast let go.
Stay away from him.
Go!
I'm just trying to save you.
Casey, the light
won't work out here now.
You have to be the one
to get Kevin to come out.
We need to get them
inside to safety.
Do you hear me?
Dad, there are two
tactical teams on the way.
Get back inside!
Hurry.
Get inside the building.
The water
used for David's room.
There's water in that tank.
I know he almost drowned
when he was a child.
Water is his weakness.
Hey!
- Hey!
- Joseph!
He's lying to you.
In comics, the parents
of the villains
always hold a key to understanding them.
He's not telling you something.
Joseph, get back!
Don't tell him yet.
Kevin's dad didn't just take
any train and not come home.
Eastrail 177.
Next stop, Philadelphia.
He took the train
my dad was on.
The one that everyone died
except my dad.
That's the key to who you are.
Mr. Glass killed Kevin's dad.
It's all evidence, you see?
If that train crash
hadn't happened,
Kevin wouldn't have been
left alone with his mother.
If Kevin's mother
wasn't allowed
to continue to abuse him,
then The Beast
wouldn't have had to be born.
What are the odds
that David Dunn
and Clarence Wendell Crumb
would be together that day?
Amazing.
I created you,
as I created David.
It just took longer.
19 years.
They almost convinced me
I was crazy.
I create superheroes.
I truly am a mastermind.
I thank you for what you did.
But I came to protect Kevin.
And I cannot trust you
to keep him safe.
Hey.
We still haven't settled
that kneeling thing.
The classic turn.
The enemy becomes the ally
because of the hero's
unflinching sense of good.
We will finish this
in front of the world.
Elijah.
Release me.
Let me talk
to Kevin Wendell Crumb.
No!
Release me.
I need to talk
to Kevin Wendell Crumb.
He needs me.
Kevin Wendell Crumb.
Hey.
The Beast listened to me.
He couldn't do what he wanted.
You can tell him what to do.
- I'm not in charge of the light.
- Yes.
Yes, you are.
It feels good.
Doesn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Will you stay
in the light with me?
For a little while?
She was able
to turn him. Target down.
You guys got to help him.
That's my dad.
He's trying to help you guys.
The guy in the green,
that's my dad.
He's trying to stop the Horde.
He's really weak.
David.
David, take my hand.
Take it now!
It's just us.
They sent me here
for you three.
Tell me the truth.
Did I almost convince you
you were an ordinary man?
I would have left you alone,
but when the Horde showed up
here, then I just had to come.
Didn't you tell me
there was a showdown
at the end of a limited edition?
How come you didn't know
how it was gonna end?
Oh, Mama.
This is not a limited edition.
This was an origin story
the whole time.
What's happening?
I like being nine.
It... it hurts, Casey.
Get it to stop hurting.
I-I can't... hold on
to the light, Casey.
I should never
have listened to her.
Now these pants
got blood on them.
They're ruined.
We got to clean
these pants, Casey.
As his body slowly
succumbs to the inevitable,
a sensation of cold water
spreads through his body.
His thoughts are a mixture
of fear and sweet relief.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here's Patricia.
We should all listen to her.
Did you see them?
They are both extraordinary.
I never doubted. I...
Never let them tell you
I doubted it.
They're all so scared.
But I told them that I'm gonna
hold the light now.
You really my friend?
Then I'm gonna hold the light
till the end.
Till the very end.
It's not so bad
being in the light.
Kevin.
Would you mind
stepping away for a moment
so I can check him?
It's okay.
They got it wrong
in the comics.
They talk about
secret evil groups
trying to stop the heroes.
I don't think
we are particularly evil,
and we don't choose sides.
We try to stop both of you.
If there is one of you,
the opposite of you appears.
It escalates.
We step in.
There just can't be
gods amongst us.
It's not fair.
It has worked just fine
for 10,000 years our way.
Take consolation in the fact
that you were right
about your theory.
Be at peace.
I wasn't a mistake, Mama.
No.
You were spectacular.
These patients
were very disturbed.
Let me just simply state,
everything that occurred
was related to drugs
in their systems
or their heightened
state of mania.
For the patients' privacy,
let's keep what happened
in this building
and this parking lot
to ourselves.
...general public alike.
Opening ceremonies
have concluded,
but from the looks on the faces
of the thousand...
All three were real.
Quite special, actually.
If you approve,
I will move to the next city.
Will there be
any repercussions?
No one saw them.
I know what my charge is.
Convince them.
This is the most humane
and effective method.
We're not executioners,
and we don't need martyrs.
If that fails, use the machine.
And I understand how important
what we're doing is.
Maintaining balance.
Keeping order.
We're not here
to buy umbrellas,
and you know it.
Spread your wings,
Mr. K.G. Bird.
We're flying you down
to headquarters.
On what charge, Boy Wonder?
Illegal umbrellas.
Assault and battery,
disturbing the peace.
We've got enough to put you
back on ice, Penguin.
He's too smart.
That's why he's the mastermind.
He'll never
tell you his real plan.
He sets everybody up.
Gets them looking
in one direction.
So cool, man.
There's always a real plan.
You see this camera?
There are 100 more of these.
Everything is being recorded.
All videos
and all backup videos
- have been erased, correct?
- Yes.
Was any of it downloaded
before that?
I don't know
how this is possible.
Someone was streaming
the live security feed
to a private site.
He went through
the basement tunnels
to be seen by
as many cameras as possible.
That's why he didn't go out
the side entrance.
He was never planning
on going to that building.
This was a suicide mission.
I gave him all the cameras
he needed right here.
What have you done, Elijah?
There are unknown forces
that don't want us to realize
what we are truly capable of.
They don't want us
to know the things we suspect
are extraordinary
about ourselves are real.
I believe that if everyone sees
what just a few people become
when they wholly embrace
their gifts,
others will awaken.
Belief in oneself
is contagious.
We give each other permission
to be superheroes.
We will never awaken
otherwise.
Whoever these people are
who don't want us
to know the truth,
today, they lose.
Thanks.
How long's it been
since we posted it?
Two hours.
How long will it be before...?
I know what this is.
This is the moment
we are let in on the universe.